{
    "id": "4e734ecafcf44421bc5ef8106f32cbb6",
    "title": "Direct And Indirect Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I asked how old you ..............................",
            "description": "Although the reporting verb is in the past tense, a present tense is possible in the reported speech if the original speaker and the reporter are in the same situation. ",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "were",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She told me that she .............................. to my father.",
            "description": "The original speaker's present perfect and past tenses are often reported using past perfect tenses. ",
            "answers": [
                "has just spoken",
                "had just spoken",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked him what ........................................",
            "description": "In reported questions constructed with who, what or which, be can go before or after the complement. ",
            "answers": [
                "was the matter",
                "the matter was",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She asked which ...............................................",
            "description": "In reported questions constructed with who, what or which, be can go before or after the complement. ",
            "answers": [
                "her seat was",
                "was her seat",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The ancient Greeks and Romans thought that the sun ........................................... around the earth.",
            "description": "The original speaker's simple present is often reported using simple past. ",
            "answers": [
                "goes",
                "went",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I want to know if I ............................................ be needed tomorrow.",
            "description": "When the reporting verb is in the present tense, the original speaker's simple future is reported using simple future. ",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He said that he ..................................... to go home and left.",
            "description": "When the reporting verb is in the past tense, the verb in the reported speech will also be in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "wants",
                "wanted",
                "had wanted"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked where ...................................... staying.",
            "description": "In reported questions, the auxiliary verb goes after the subject. ",
            "answers": [
                "the minister was",
                "was the minister",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I knew how .......................................",
            "description": "The auxiliary do is not used in reported questions. ",
            "answers": [
                "did she feel",
                "she felt",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He suggested ....................................... quit.",
            "description": "Infinitive structures cannot be used after suggest. ",
            "answers": [
                "me to",
                "that I should",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The doctor said ........................................... smoking.",
            "description": "Infinitive structures cannot be used after say. ",
            "answers": [
                "me to quit",
                "that I must quit",
                "quitting"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He said that he .................................. Maria at the club a few days before.",
            "description": "The original speaker's present perfect and past tenses are often reported using past perfect tenses. ",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "has seen",
                "had seen"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}